securedatarecovery.com 2019-01-31

# Privacy Policy - Secure Data Recovery Services

**Effective Date: 9/27/2018**

  * This privacy policy applies to www.securedatarecovery.com owned and operated by Secure Data Recovery Services. This privacy policy describes how Secure Data Recovery Services collects and uses the personal information you provide on our web site: www.securedatarecovery.com, mobile app and our Services. The use of information collected through our service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the Client has engaged Secure Data Recovery Services. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.

At Secure Data Recovery Services, we greatly respect our clients' privacy. We were the first data recovery provider to earn a SSAE 16 Type II certification, and over the years, we have built a strong reputation for our commitment to security and transparency. 

We provide a detailed overview of our practices to help you use our website. Contact our customer service department if you have any questions regarding the terms listed below. 

The use of information collected through our service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the Client has engaged Secure Data Recovery Services. 

Secure Data Recovery Services participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Secure Data Recovery Services is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, respectively, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework's applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Frameworks, visit the [U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). 

Secure Data Recovery Services is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Frameworks, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Secure Data Recovery Services complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions. 

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, Secure Data Recovery Services is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Secure Data Recovery Services may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. 

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>. 

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website, you may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted. 

## Collecting and Using Personal Information

Secure Data Recovery Services collects basic information for internal use. This includes but is not limited to phone numbers and addresses entered into our online evaluation form or information collected over the phone when you call our customer service department. We also collect your first and last name, email address and phone number, when you send us a request regarding our services, credit card information to make payments for invoices using our payment processor and photos for job applications on the site. When you use our media services, we keep your information strictly confidential. 

We only use your information for the primary purpose of contacting you, creating your account with us, assessing your needs and responding to your customer service requests. 

## Information Disclosure Guidelines

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties. 

Secure Data Recovery Services does not share any personal or corporate information except for the purposes of providing requested products and services. In the event that we need to share personally identifiable information with equipment manufacturers or other third parties, we will request your permission prior to doing so. 

We may share your information with third parties who provide services on our behalf to help with our business activities. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. 

**These services may include:**

  * Fulfilling orders and delivering packages
  * Payment processing
  * Providing customer service
  * Sending marketing communications
  * Fulfilling subscription services
  * Conducting research and analysis
  * Providing cloud computing infrastructure 

We may also use aggregated information for general purposes including but not limited to advertising, sales or mergers. This information will not include phone numbers, addresses, payment numbers or other personally identifiable data. 

In certain situations, Secure Data Recovery Services may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. 

Secure Data Recovery Services may be obligated to respond to subpoenas or other legal processes. We reserve the right to share information in order to prevent illegal activities or to aid in the investigation and prosecution of illegal activities as required by law and when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others. We also reserve the right to use collected information to defend against lawsuits, to establish fault or for other legal reasons not explicitly listed in these terms. 

If Secure Data Recovery Services is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information. 

## User Access and Choice

Upon request Secure Data Recovery Services will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your personal information. To request this information please email us at [legal@securedatarecovery.com](mailto:legal@securedatarecovery.com). 

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, delete or deactivate it by emailing our Customer Support at [customercare@securedatarecovery.com](mailto:customercare@securedatarecovery.com) or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days. 

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

## Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as login credentials and credit card information) on our forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). 

We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at [legal@securedatarecovery.com](mailto:legal@securedatarecovery.com). 

## Cookie Collection

SecureDataRecovery.com uses cookies to provide a better experience for our website visitors. Cookies are small files stored on your computer that allow SecureDataRecovery.com to identify and differentiate between different users. 

Most websites use cookies in some way. Cookies are limited and do not allow us to access any files on your computer. You may delete cookies at any time by consulting your web browser's documentation. 

You may also consult your browser's documentation if you do not wish to receive cookies or if you want to be notified when websites use cookies. If you turn off cookies, you may not be able to use certain functions and features of SecureDataRecovery.com. 

## Tracking Technologies

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you. 

Our website also uses Google Analytics, a popular web traffic analytics tool. Google Analytics adds cookies to your computer when you visit SecureDataRecovery.com and collects information about the website traffic. See [**Google's privacy policy**](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ "Google privacy policy") for more information. 

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by us and our third party partners (Marketing partners), affiliates, or analytics or service providers (online customer support provider). These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. 

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [**here**](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/ "Opt-out Ads for United States") (or if located in the European Union click [**here**](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/ "Opt-out Ads for Europe")) Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads. 

When you download and use our Services, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use, operating system version, and the device identifier (or "UDID").  

We send you push notifications from time-to-time in order to update you about any events or promotions that we may be running. If you no longer wish to receive these types of communications, you may turn them off at the device level. To ensure you receive proper notifications, we will need to collect certain information about your device such as operating system and user identification information.  

We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our Mobile Software on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information you submit within the mobile application.  

## Limitation of Liability

By using our services, you acknowledge that any item shipped to our offices (hereafter referred to as "media") may be damaged during shipment and/or lost prior to receipt. You agree that Secure Data Recovery Services cannot be held liable for any damage or loss that occurs before we receive your media. 

At Secure Data Recovery Services, we take care to protect our clients' media and always use safe techniques to recover files. We treat physically damaged media in a certified Class 10 ISO 4 Cleanroom and hold certifications from many major manufacturers that demonstrate our commitment to providing consistently safe services. However, due to the sensitive nature of data recovery and media repair, we cannot accept liability for any damage that may occur to your equipment/data/media at our facilities. 

Secure Data Recovery Services cannot be held liable for any indirect media damage or data loss. You agree that Secure Data Recovery Services cannot be held liable for any damages that occur due to any virus, Trojan horse or other malicious application. The total liability of Secure Data Recovery Services to customer cannot exceed the total cost of services. 

To safely treat your media, we may need to ship your hard drive to our offsite facility or corporate headquarters. We reserve the right to ship your hard drive as needed in order to complete our services. 

We cannot accept payments in excess of $3000.00 USD via credit card. Secure Data Recovery reserves the right to dispose of external hard drive enclosures or other components during our diagnostics process in order to ensure fast turnaround times. 

Secure Data Recovery is not responsible for loss of profit or any other damages incurred by our customers during the data recovery process or return shipment. Secure Data Recovery will also not be held responsible or liable for any damage to desktop computers, servers, laptops or any other hardware. 

## Information Related to Data Collected for our Clients

Secure Data Recovery collects information under the direction of its Clients, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. If you are a customer of one of our Clients and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Clients that use our service, please contact the Client that you interact with directly. We may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the service agreements with our Clients. 

An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct his query to the Secure Data Recovery’s Client (the data controller). If requested to access or remove data we will respond within 30 days. 

We will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Clients for as long as needed to provide services to our Client. Secure Data Recovery will retain this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

## Confidentiality and Security

Secure Data Recovery Services limits access to our customers' information to our staff members who need said information in order to provide requested services to you and your business. We may also share information at our discretion with reputable equipment manufacturers in the course of providing our services. These third party service providers, (such as manufacturers), are authorized to use your data diagnostics only as necessary to provide these services to us. 

Secure Data Recovery Services may sign confidentiality agreements if requested; the terms of those agreements may reinforce this agreement but will not supersede this agreement unless they contain an explicit statement to this effect. We maintain a strict non-disclosure agreement, and all of our employees and vendors comply with this agreement. 

## Preferences

You may sign-up to receive emails or newsletters or other communications from us. If you would like to discontinue receiving this information, you may update your email preferences by using the “Unsubscribe” link found in emails we send to you or by contacting us at [legal@securedatarecovery.com](mailto:legal@securedatarecovery.com). 

## Links to 3rd Party Sites

Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Secure Data Recovery Services. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit. 

## Testimonials

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [**legal@securedatarecovery.com**](mailto:legal@securedatarecovery.com "Email Our Legal Department"). 

## Blogs

Our blog is also managed by a third party application that may require you to register to post a comment. We do not have access or control of the information posted to the blog. You will need to contact or login into the third party application if you want the personal information that was posted to the comments section removed. To learn how the third party application uses your information, please review their privacy policy. 

## Social Media Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook and Twitter buttons and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

Secure Data Recovery Services may apply changes or updates to this policy as needed. Most changes are for additional clarity and will not affect the quality of our services. We will notify you about significant changes by placing a notice on our website or by sending you an email; however, prior to the change becoming effective. By using our services, you agree to our present terms and conditions. 

## Questions and Suggestions

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our company or our terms of service, please contact us by e-mail: [**legal@securedatarecovery.com**](mailto:legal@securedatarecovery.com "Email Our Legal Department") or through our mailing address below: 

3255 Cahuenga Blvd. West, #301 Los Angeles, CA 90068
